<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: psylink -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.label>пси-зв'язок</PsychicAmplifier.label>
  <!-- EN: An organic connection to a larger psychic field. This allows a person to psychically induce a distant archotech superintelligence to influence reality in ways that seem impossible.\n\nHigher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. Regardless of psylink level, a person can only use specific powers that they have learned.\n\nPsylink comes from a variety of sources. Single-use psylink neuroformer devices can create a psylink. Tribal peoples also know how to develop it through ritual linking with the legendary anima tree.\n\nAs a physical phenomenon in the brain, psylink is poorly-understood by scientists, not least because it seems to actively conceal itself if studied too closely. One thing most agree on is that it somehow connects people to archotechs and harnesses their power, possibly through some sort of negotiation or sympathy mechanism. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.description>Органічний зв'язок з широким пси-полем, що дозволяє його володарю спонукати надрозум далекого архотека впливати на навколишню дійсність важкозрозумілими способами.\n\nЧим вищий рівень пси-зв'язку, тим більше різних можливостей можна використовувати. Незалежно від рівня, людина може застосовувати лише вивчені нею пси-здатності\n\nПси-зв'язок можна встановити різними способами. Для її штучного формування використовують спеціальний одноразовий нейроформер. У багатьох племенах навчилися розвивати її за допомогою ритуального зв'язування з легендарним древом душі. \n\nЯк фізичне явище, пси-зв'язок погано піддається науковому поясненню, не в останню чергу тому, що він, здається, активно приховує себе, якщо вивчати його надто уважно. Вчені сходяться на думці, що пси-зв'язок якимось чином поєднує людей з архотеками і дозволяє використовувати їхню силу, можливо, через певний механізм переговорів або симпатії.</PsychicAmplifier.description>
  <!-- EN: Allows a person to psychically-induce an archotech to influence reality in ways that seem impossible. Higher levels of psylink permit the use of more powers. -->
  <PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>Дозволяє людині спонукати далекого архотека впливати на навколишню дійсність важкозрозумілими способами. Чим вищий рівень пси-зв'язку, тим більше різних можливостей можна використовувати.</PsychicAmplifier.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>
