<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <!-- natural -->

  <Heart.label>heart</Heart.label>
  <Heart.description>A biological human heart. Pumps blood around the body.</Heart.description>

  <Lung.label>lung</Lung.label>
  <Lung.description>A biological human lung. A pair of these form the core of the human respiratory system.</Lung.description>

  <Kidney.label>kidney</Kidney.label>
  <Kidney.description>A biological human kidney. Filters and removes waste products from the blood.</Kidney.description>

  <Liver.label>liver</Liver.label>
  <Liver.description>A biological human liver. Plays an important role in metabolism.</Liver.description>


  <!-- simple prosthetics (industrial tech) -->

  <SimpleProstheticLeg.label>prosthetic leg</SimpleProstheticLeg.label>
  <SimpleProstheticLeg.description>A leg prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real leg.</SimpleProstheticLeg.description>

  <SimpleProstheticArm.label>prosthetic arm</SimpleProstheticArm.label>
  <SimpleProstheticArm.description>An arm prosthesis. While it lacks a neural interface, its complex arrangement of internal joints allows it to mimic natural movement quite convincingly. Still, it is inferior to a real arm.</SimpleProstheticArm.description>

  <SimpleProstheticHeart.label>prosthetic heart</SimpleProstheticHeart.label>
  <SimpleProstheticHeart.description>A heart prosthesis. It contains an electric motor that pumps blood smoothly around the body. Users often report feeling tired, but it's better than the alternative.</SimpleProstheticHeart.description>

  <CochlearImplant.label>cochlear implant</CochlearImplant.label>
  <CochlearImplant.description>An implant which replaces normal hearing. An external microphone transmits a sound signal to electrodes wrapped around the inner ear's auditory sensing nerves. The electrodes stimulate the nerves according to the sound, creating a sensation of hearing. It's not as good as a natural ear, but it's a lot better than being deaf.</CochlearImplant.description>


  <!-- bionics (spacer tech) -->

  <BionicEye.label>bionic eye</BionicEye.label>
  <BionicEye.description>An advanced artifical eye. With its biogel nerve-link, internal signal pre-processor, and wide-spectrum sensors, it is better than a biological eye in almost every way. A lattice-dust healing system allows it to recover from damage.</BionicEye.description>

  <BionicArm.label>bionic arm</BionicArm.label>
  <BionicArm.description>An advanced artificial arm. Silenced mini-servos give great strength, while the biogel nerve-link gives exquisite control. A lattice-dust healing system allows it to recover from damage. It is better than a biological arm in almost every way.</BionicArm.description>

  <BionicLeg.label>bionic leg</BionicLeg.label>
  <BionicLeg.description>An advanced artificial leg. With its biogel nerve-link, powerful mini-servos, and lattice-dust healing system, it is better than a biological leg in almost every way.</BionicLeg.description>

  <BionicSpine.label>bionic spine</BionicSpine.label>
  <BionicSpine.description>An advanced artificial spine. A biogel nerve bundle runs down an articulated plasteel core, surrounded by a lattice-dust healing system. It matches the performance of a biological spine.</BionicSpine.description>

  <BionicHeart.label>bionic heart</BionicHeart.label>
  <BionicHeart.description>An advanced artificial heart. It has synthetic muscle fibers for a realistic heartbeat, plus a high-flow pump for rapid circulation during high stress. It is better than a biological heart in almost every way.</BionicHeart.description>

  <BionicStomach.label>bionic stomach</BionicStomach.label>
  <BionicStomach.description>An advanced artificial stomach. A set of sensors and chemical synthesizers efficiently digest nearly any energy-bearing foodstuff. An integrated lattice-dust healing system automatically repairs any damage caused by the powerful acids. It is better than a biological stomach in almost every way.</BionicStomach.description>

  <BionicEar.label>bionic ear</BionicEar.label>
  <BionicEar.description>An advanced artificial ear implant. A collection of invisible subdermal microphones capture sound and transmit it to a biogel nerve interface that links directly with the auditory nerve. It's sensitive enough to hear a cat before you see it, can't be damaged by loud noise, and automatically tunes itself to pick out meaningful sounds in noisy environments.</BionicEar.description>


  <!-- bionic non-makeable -->

  <PowerClaw.label>power claw</PowerClaw.label>
  <PowerClaw.description>A combat-oriented hand replacement consisting of a mechanical hand with a vicious claw on each finger. It is vicious in combat, and its powerful mini-servos can crush a skull like a natural hand crushes an egg. The blades can be retracted, making it as useful as a biological hand for non-combat tasks.</PowerClaw.description>


  <!-- archotech -->

  <ArchotechEye.label>archotech eye</ArchotechEye.label>
  <ArchotechEye.description>An artifical eye built by an archotech. It perceives every type of electromagnetic radiation, including radio waves, infrared, light, x-rays, and gamma rays. Its visual acuity is precise enough to read handwriting from twenty meters away. It can emit various wavelengths of radiation like a flashlight, and has an internal subpersona AI which helps highlight useful visual information. Externally, it looks like a natural human eye, except it can change color at will. Its internal workings are a mystery to all human minds.</ArchotechEye.description>

  <ArchotechArm.label>archotech arm</ArchotechArm.label>
  <ArchotechArm.description>An artifical arm built by an archotech. It's strong enough to crush a thick hardwood branch in its hand, and precise enough to write a sonnet on a grain of rice. It looks and feels like natural flesh, but it's harder to damage than plasteel. Even if it is harmed, it repairs itself over time. Its internal workings are a mystery to all human minds.</ArchotechArm.description>

  <ArchotechLeg.label>archotech leg</ArchotechLeg.label>
  <ArchotechLeg.description>An artifical leg built by an archotech. It looks and feels like natural flesh, but a pair of these can move the user as fast as a decent car, and it's harder to damage than plasteel. Even if it is harmed, it repairs itself over time. Its internal workings are a mystery to all human minds.</ArchotechLeg.description>


</LanguageData>
