<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <Peaceful.label>peaceful</Peaceful.label>
  <Peaceful.description>Будуйте спільноту в режимі пісочниці.\n\nРекомендовано для гравців, які бажають зосередитися на аспектах будівництва спільноти у RimWorld.\n\nЦей режим вимикає основні загрози, але проблеми, такі як хвороби, психічні зриви та скажені тварини, все ще відбуваються.</Peaceful.description>

  <Easy.label>builder</Easy.label>
  <Easy.description>Build a colony, while still having a taste of danger.\n\nRecommended for: Players who are new to this kind of game, and players who want to build a perfect colony.\n\nMajor threats appear, but they're weaker than other modes. Деякі надзвичайні небезпеки вимкнені.</Easy.description>

  <Medium.label>medium</Medium.label>
  <Medium.description>Build a community while facing down dangerous threats.\n\nRecommended for: Experienced strategy game players on their first game of RimWorld, or skilled RimWorld players who want some breathing room to pursue funny or weird goals.\n\nThere's room to grow and thrive, but it's still a dangerous planet.</Medium.description>

  <Rough.label>rough</Rough.label>
  <Rough.description>Strive to survive on a rough, tough planet.\n\nRecommended for: Players with experience with RimWorld, looking to play a rough story requiring skill to survive.\n\nThere will be good times and bad times; triumph and tragedy. It's all for the drama.</Rough.description>

  <Hard.label>savage</Hard.label>
  <Hard.description>Face brutal survival challenges. The price of survival is blood.\n\nRecommended for: Experienced players who want to experience great tests and sacrifice.\n\nSucceeding at this level requires diverse strategies, disciplined preparation, and luck. Threats can spike and combine in vicious ways. Even if you play well, some challenges will be impossible to overcome without losses.</Hard.description>

  <Extreme.label>merciless</Extreme.label>
  <Extreme.description>Apply mastery of every RimWorld skill for just a chance to survive a harrowing trial against a merciless, unfair world.\n\nRecommended for: Experienced players who want to face a brutal, unfair challenge where even great skill may not prevent death.\n\nThis level is about dealing with losses, because preventing them is impossible. You'll spend a lot of time fighting wounded and recovering, and you'll need to sacrifice people and things you love. Unfair challenges and capricious death may come at any time.</Extreme.description>


</LanguageData>
