<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!-- EN: acolyte -->
  <Acolyte.label>аколіт</Acolyte.label>
  <!-- EN: The title of acolyte is the title of senior learners in the psychic cult, and encompasses a wide range of practical positions. Some acolytes are purely students, learning to lead troops, manage societies, or use psycasts in specialized schools. Others come from wealthy families and might own city buildings or farm complexes.\n\nDuring wartime, an acolyte might lead a platoon of troops, captain a small frigate, or serve their liege as an advisor. -->
  <Acolyte.description>The title of acolyte is the title of senior learners in the psychic cult, and encompasses a wide range of practical positions. Some acolytes are purely students, learning to lead troops, manage societies, or use psycasts in specialized schools. Others come from wealthy families and might own city buildings or farm complexes.\n\nDuring wartime, an acolyte might lead a platoon of troops, captain a small frigate, or serve their liege as an advisor.</Acolyte.description>
  <!-- EN: baron -->
  <Baron.label>барон</Baron.label>
  <!-- EN: The title of baron is the lowest of the psychic lords who can act as a semi-independent ruler. Most barons are subordinate to a higher lord. The baron is obliged to provide both personal service as a warrior or advisor, and economic support like money and troops.\n\nIn the Empire, a baron will typically own a city sector, mining colony, or similar outfit. At wartime, a baron may captain a capital ship in name, or control a regiment of soldiers. -->
  <Baron.description>Титул барон — це найнижчий титул серед середнього кола дворян. У той час як нижчі титули зосереджуються на особистій службі, війні чи торгівлі під керівництвом лорда, барони є напівнезалежними правителями. Кожен барон підпорядковується своєму лорду, але його обов’язки здебільшого полягають у постачанні багатства та війська, а не безпосередньо в особистому служінні.\n\nВ імперії барон, як правило, володіє міським сектором, шахтарською колонією тощо. Під час війни барон може бути капітаном головного корабля або командувати військовим полком.</Baron.description>
  <!-- EN: consul -->
  <Consul.label>консул</Consul.label>
  <!-- EN: The Imperial title of consul is a lower level of high nobility.\n\nIn the Empire, consuls control planets. At war, a consul can usually field an army-sized force of multiple divisions, supported by several fleets. Some command from a super-capital ship or control space-based megastructures. -->
  <Consul.description>Консул — це найнижчий імперський титул вищого кола дворян.\n\nВ імперії консули контролюють планети. На війні консул зазвичай може розгорнути армію чисельністю в декілька дивізій за підтримки кількох флотів. Дехто командує з головного корабля імперського флоту або керує космічними мегаструктурами.</Consul.description>
  <!-- EN: archon -->
  <Count.label>граф</Count.label>
  <!-- EN: The title of archon is middle rank among the independent members of the psychic cult.\n\nIn peacetime, an archon may rule to a city or colony. A successful archon might have a small personal fleet, possibly including capital ships. -->
  <Count.description>Титул графа це середній рівень середнього кола дворян.\n\nУ мирний час графи володіють містом або колонією і можуть мати невеликий особистий флот, можливо, включаючи великі кораблі.</Count.description>
  <!-- EN: dominus -->
  <Duke.label>герцог</Duke.label>
  <!-- EN: The Imperial title of dominus is the highest of the middle-ranked independent rulers.\n\nIn the Empire, domini control provinces, mega-cities, or moons. At war, a dominus can field a division-level force, or a fleet with capital ships and dozens of support craft. -->
  <Duke.description>Герцог — це найвищий імперський титул середнього кола дворян.\n\nВ імперії герцоги контролюють провінції, мегаміста або природні супутники. На війні герцог може розгорнути військові дивізії або флот із великими кораблями та десятками допоміжних кораблів.</Duke.description>
  <!-- EN: emperor -->
  <Emperor.label>імператор</Emperor.label>
  <!-- EN: The Imperial title of emperor indicates sovereign dominion over the entire Empire, all its peoples, planets, and fleets. All other lords swear fealty to a high lord, while the Emperor swears fealty to no one. However, even the Emperor depends on the support of lower nobles to remain in power. -->
  <Emperor.description>Титул Імператор вказує на суверенне панування над усією Імперією, усіма її народами, планетами та флотами. Усі інші лорди присягають на вірність Імператору, а Імператор нікому не присягає на вірність. Однак навіть імператор залежить від підтримки нижчих дворян, щоб залишитися при владі.</Emperor.description>
  <!-- EN: empress -->
  <Emperor.labelFemale>імператриця</Emperor.labelFemale>
  <!-- EN: freeholder -->
  <Freeholder.label>фригольдер</Freeholder.label>
  <!-- EN: The Imperial title of freeholder is used by the Empire to signifies a fully-respected individual. Most Imperial citizens earn it while young through volunteer work or military service. The title is also offered to outsiders who act with honor in the eyes of the Empire. -->
  <Freeholder.description>Фригольдер — це імперський титул який використовується Імперією для позначення шанованої особи. Більшість громадян Імперії заробляють його в молодості волонтерською роботою або військовою службою. Титул також пропонується чужакам, які діють з честю в інтересах Імперії.</Freeholder.description>
  <!-- EN: knight -->
  <Knight.label>лицар</Knight.label>
  <!-- EN: The title of knight is held by agents of the psychic cult who have fully passed their training, but who have not ascended to higher leadership roles. Many knights never advance further, and spend their lives as respected warriors, advisors, or commanders.\n\nIn war, some knights lead troop companies and assault squadrons, while psychic-focused knights engage in espionage, sabotage, and battlefield psychic combat. -->
  <Knight.description>Титул лицаря носять дворяни, які в основному пройшли навчання, але не досягли вищих лідерських посад. Багато лицарів ніколи не просуваються далі й проводять своє життя як шановані менеджери, радники чи воїни.\n\nБільшість лицарів мають певні багатства, але деякі залишаються досить бідними, тоді як інші можуть бути дуже багатими.\n\nУ мирний час лицар може керувати фабричним комплексом, комерційним районом або малим фермерським регіоном. Під час війни деякі лицарі очолюють роти військ і штурмові загони, тоді як лицарі із пси-здібностями, беруть участь у шпигунстві, диверсіях і ведуть психічну битву на полі бою.</Knight.description>
  <!-- EN: praetor -->
  <Praetor.label>претор</Praetor.label>
  <!-- EN: The title of praetor denotes a member of the psychic cult who carries out field missions in a more senior role than a mere knight. Praetors often act alone, but may also command knights and lower members.\n\nDuring peacetime, a praetor will usually manage a city district, asteroid sector, or agricultural region. During war, they take authority over the smallest independent combat units - terrestrial troop cohorts, or space-borne destroyers or combat groups. -->
  <Praetor.description>The title of praetor denotes a member of the psychic cult who carries out field missions in a more senior role than a mere knight. Praetors often act alone, but may also command knights and lower members.\n\nDuring peacetime, a praetor will usually manage a city district, asteroid sector, or agricultural region. During war, they take authority over the smallest independent combat units - terrestrial troop cohorts, or space-borne destroyers or combat groups.</Praetor.description>
  <!-- EN: stellarch -->
  <Stellarch.label>стелларх</Stellarch.label>
  <!-- EN: The Imperial title of stellarch represents dominion over an entire star system.\n\nIn the Empire, since interstellar travel times are years long, stellarchs rule their systems with a great degree of independence. They each swear fealty to the Emperor, but since the Emperor may be many light-years away, a stellarch may go years or decades without interacting with him. -->
  <Stellarch.description>Імперський титул стелларха означає панування над цілою зоряною системою.\n\nВ Імперії, оскільки час міжзоряних подорожей триває роки, стеллархи керують своїми системами з великим ступенем незалежності. Кожен з них присягає на вірність Імператору, але оскільки Імператор може бути за багато світлових років, стелларх може роками чи десятиліттями не взаємодіяти з ним.</Stellarch.description>
  <!-- EN: novice -->
  <Yeoman.label>йомен</Yeoman.label>
  <!-- EN: The Imperial title of novice is held by those who have recently been initiated into the ranks of the psychic cult. It gives the holder the right to use low-level psychic abilities as part of their learning.\n\nThis title is often held by senior soldiers, warskiff pilots, spies, advisors, diplomats, intrusion operatives, and other key individuals. Many important people spend their entire lives as novices. -->
  <Yeoman.description>Імператорський титул йомена носять ті, хто служить знатному лорду особливим чином. Хоча це не дворянський титул, він дає власнику право використовувати пси-здібності низького рівня.\n\nЦей титул часто носять старші солдати, пілоти бойових скіфів, шпигуни, радники, дипломати, оперативники вторгнення та інші ключові особи. Багато важливих людей проводять все своє життя як йомени, прагнучи досягти успіху поза обмеженнями дворянства.</Yeoman.description>
</LanguageData>
